[MUSIC]
The short straddle seller is hoping for
a lack of movement in the price of
the underlying shares and
is indifferent to direction.
It is a fairly pure ban on decreasing
volatility, and benefits from decay.
A short straddle is created when
an investor sells an equal number of calls
and ports with the same strike and
expiration.
It may be used when investors expect
a decrease in either implied volatility or
a lack of movement in the price
of the underlying equity.
Profit is limited to the initial premium
received while loss is potentially
unlimited.
The direction of the stock does
not matter to the straddle seller,
as long as the movement up or
down from the strike stays within
the price received for the straddle.
The maximum gain is
the cost of the trade and
occurs if the stock closes
at the strike price.
Time decay helps a straddle seller.
The combination has two breakeven
points equal to the strike price plus
the cost of the trade, and the strike
price minus the cost of the trade.
The straddle seller, loses money if the
underlying price exceeds a range around
the strike price,
beyond the total premium received.
[MUSIC]